

SHCHERBAKOV ALEKSANDR

+7 (923) 758-93-84 <u>self@xash.cc</u>

Nahimova 20, St. Petersburg <u>xash.cc</u>

My goal is to build ambient computing systems which seamlessly enhance user experience. I explore the latest research at the intersection of edge networking, computer graphics and artificial intelligence to outline inclusive, sustainable and effortless medium for the human-computer interaction of tomorrow.

EDUCATION

Sep 2018 – Jun 2022 ITMO University

Bachelor of Science, magna cum laude

Field: Infocommunication Technologies and Network Systems

Thesis: Serverless Decision-Making Service for University Admission

GPA: 4.85 (national) / 4.76 (adjusted)

PROJECTS

Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

Bachelor Thesis

Abitu

UI/UX Design; Back-end, Front-end and Data Engineer

- Applied serverless architecture for a university admission platform
- Deployed backend service, frontend application, data processing and database cluster to countrywide infrastructure
- Achieved near-instant response time under virtually unlimited load by using on-demand static site generation
- Moved extract-transform-load pipeline to a chain of cloud workers with pinpoint debugging and orchestration
- Introduced an simplified metric for admission probability
- Designed and implemented a sophisticated web interface with a unified and easily comparable data presentation

September 2021

Wunder

Tech Internship

Back-end Engineer, Data Engineer

• Built a CEFR language-level classification pipeline for news articles and wrapped it into REST API for Android application

PAGE 1 OF 4 XASH.CC/CV

 Parsed textbook wordlists and news pieces, developed a method for word complexity rating, established text feature extracting process and trained a classification model

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

Durasov House

Joint with HSE Design

UI/UX Design, Consultant

- Enhanced user experience for an AR museum application by introducing video-game elements to a conventional guide
- Created a versatile design system which allowed for text, audio and AR multimedia to be used seamlessly

December 2018

Suffragor

Hackaton

Back-end Engineer

- Built a REST API for an Ethereum-based smart contract election system over the course of a 48-hour hackathon
- Adapted T-Systems' experimental blockchain platform for on-premise applications

CURRENT

Aug 2022 -

Buben

UI/UX Design, iOS Developer, Back-end Engineer

- · Exploring modern censorship-circumvention methods
- Adapting an experimental QUIC Proxy protocol for Darwinbased devices. Leveraging scale-to-zero infrastructure for a highperformance proxy service
- Developing a simple interface for a VPN client with contextual user assistance for connection edge cases

WORK EXPERIENCE

October 2019 -

Business Partner

UI/UX Design, Back-end Engineer, iOS Developer

- Co-developing mobile applications for small to medium enterprises
- Designing cross-platform adaptive interfaces
- Maintaining and updating iOS applications
- Managing Firebase infrastructure

PAGE 2 OF 4 XASH.CC/CV

August 2016 -

Contractor

St 2010

Cut The Crap TV

Motion Graphics Engineer

- Providing motion graphics for a web content production with over 2 million subscribers across all media platforms
- Exploring modern computer imagery tools for consistent signature visual narrative
- Incorporating diffusion model art generation, virtual production in Unreal Engine and neural radiance field photogrammetry into blockbuster-style videos

Jul 2016 - Aug 2016

Meta.Studio

Internship

Web Developer

- Assisted in redesigning local e-commerce website
- Created motion graphics and interactive JavaScript elements for the landing page

ADMINISTRATIVE WORK

Aug 2020 - Mar 2021

Student Distance Learning Task Group

Founder and Chairman

- Negotiated conditions for remote education with tutors and faculty administration
- Accelerated the transition from university intranet mail to modern social platforms such as Discord and Telegram
- Participated in the development of the new schedule that took into account different timezones
- Managed social environments by establishing guidelines for announcements, messages and file sharing

ADVISING EXPERIENCE

May 2020

Samsung IT School Russia

Mentor

- Co-advised a team of high school students for the grand finals of the national Android application contest
- Guided team's decisions over product goals, interactions and user experience
- The team earned an audience award for the best social application

PAGE 3 OF 4 XASH.CC/CV

Nov 2020 - April 2021

HSE Design

Advisor

- Assisted with the implementation of Durasov museum UI
- Provided feedback on establishing a consistent user experience over physical and virtual elements

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Dec 2022 - Dec 2024

TOEFL iBT

107 out of 120

Reading: 30 (Advanced) Listening: 30 (Advanced)

Speaking: 21 (High Intermediate)

Writing: 26 (Advanced)

PAGE 4 OF 4 XASH.CC/CV